ネット:network, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 設計[せっけい]:plan/design/layout, 開発[かいはつ, かいほつ]:development/exploitation, 過程[かてい]:process/course/mechanism
（ヤサコ）ネットのウワサによると
メガネの設計や開発の過程は―
According to rumors on the net,
the process of creating and developing the glasses
複雑[ふくざつ]:complex/complicated/mixed (feelings), 利権[りけん]:interest/rights/concession, 歴史[れきし]:history, 彩る[いろどる]:to colour|to apply make-up|to decorate
複雑な利権と歴史に
彩られているそうです
encompasses a complex history with many interesting points.
（ハラケン）僕を…
Take me...
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 連れる[つれる]:to lead/to take (a person)
僕をあっちに連れて行ってくれ！
Take me to "the other side"!
構う[かまう]:to mind|to care for|to prepare for||, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at
（オバちゃん）
構うな！　イサコだけを狙え
Don't mind them!
Just chase Isako!
作戦[さくせん]:tactics/strategy|military or naval operations, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
（猫目(ねこめ)）猫目だ　作戦を忘れるな
通路が開くのを待つんだ
It's me, Nekome! Don't forget the plan!
Wait for the passage to open!
やはり:too/also|still, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
（オバちゃん）やはり
通路を開かせるわけにはいかないわ
I'm still convinced we shouldn't let her open the passage!
（猫目）何？
What?!
現行犯[げんこうはん]:flagrante delicto/caught red-handed, 捕らえる[とらえる]:to catch|to grasp (e.g. meaning)|to captivate, リスク:risk, リスク:reduced instruction set computer/RISC, 冒す[おかす]:to brave|to harm|to desecrate|, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|
（オバちゃん）
今 現行犯で捕らえれば
リスクを冒さずに済む
If we catch her in the act, we can end the story without further risk!
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 狙う[ねらう]:to aim at
イサコの電脳体を狙え！
Shoot at Isako's cyberbody!
（オバちゃん）なんだ？
What?
攻撃[こうげき]:attack/strike|criticism, システム:system, 内部[ないぶ]:interior/inside/internal
（オバちゃん）
攻撃はシステム内部から？
The attack came from inside the system?
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|, 止まる[とまる]:to stop (moving)|to stop (doing, working, being supplied)|to alight, 止まる[とどまる]:to remain/to abide|to be limited to
マズい… タマ 止まれ！
Terrible!
Tama! Stop!
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway
（猫目）通路はどうだ？
How about the passage?
起動[きどう]:startup/booting up/activation, リンク:link/directory entry
起動しているわ　リンクは？
It's opening up...
What about the link?
つながる:to be tied together/to be connected to|to lead to
（猫目）まだ つながらない
It hasn't connected yet.
逃す[のがす]:to miss (e.g. a chance)|to set free|to fail to ...
（オバちゃん）逃したのか？
What happened?
遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|, まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected
遅い… まさかウソを？
Late...
Is it possible she lied?
カンナ？
Kanna...
The door to another world
Maybe the passage already opened?
すでに:already/too late, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 起動[きどう]:startup/booting up/activation
すでに通路は起動しているのか
周囲[しゅうい]:surroundings/environs|circumference, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 破壊[はかい]:destruction/disruption|(application) crash
周囲の暗号を破壊しろ！
Destroy the encodes around here!
間に合う[まにあう]:to be in time for|to serve (suit, meet) the purpose/to be good enough
間に合ってくれ
Please make it in time...
勝手に[かってに]:arbitrarily/of its own accord/voluntarily, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||
（イサコ）
あいつ 勝手に動くなと言ったのに
That guy...
I told him not to move without permission!
暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 破壊[はかい]:destruction/disruption|(application) crash, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 現れる[あらわれる]:to appear/to come in sight|to be expressed (e.g. emotions), 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 制御[せいぎょ]:control/governing/checking
暗号を破壊されたら
通路が現れる場所を制御できない
If the encode is destroyed,
I won't be able to control where the passage leads to!
クソ！
Crap!
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
もし あいつ
先に入ってしまったら…
If that guy enters first...
カンナ…
Kanna...
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway
（ハラケン）これが… 通路？
This is...
the passage!
What a difficult encode...
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 固い[かたい]:hard|stiff|strong||, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 式[しき]:equation|ceremony|style|
（オバちゃん）なんて固い暗号式だ
撃ち方[うちかた]:way to shoot/how to shoot
撃ち方 やめ！
Stop firing!
I got it wrong...
違う…
This is an encode to control the position of the passage!
位置[いち]:place/situation/position, 制御[せいぎょ]:control/governing/checking, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher
これは位置を制御する暗号だ
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway
通路か
The passage!
The passage...
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
通路が開いたのか？
opened up?
Kanna...
カンナ…
The passage opened!
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, リンク:link/directory entry
通路が開いた　リンクは？
The link?
つながる:to be tied together/to be connected to|to lead to, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 探す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
（猫目）まだ つながらない
お前は通路を探せ
It hasn't connected yet.
Find the passage.
Finally...
やっと:at last/at length|barely, 会[え]:gathering (esp. Buddhist, festive, etc.), 会[かい]:meeting/assembly|association
やっと… やっと会えた
Finally I can meet you!
Kanna!
カンナ！
Oh no!
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|
マズい！
Haraken!
ハラケン！
Yasako...
ヤサコ？
He's here...
近く[ちかく]:near|nearly (e.g. "it took nearly one year")|shortly
いる 近くにいる
He's around here!
It's this way!
こっちだわ
Kanna!
カンナ 僕は…
I...
Haraken!
ハラケン
Crap! Where is it?
クソ！　どこだ？
あっ あれだ！
It's there!
Kanna!
カンナ！
It's closing...
閉じる[とじる]:to close (e.g. book, eyes, meeting, etc.)/to shut, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
閉じる… 閉じてしまう！
It will close up!
なんてことだ… ハッ！
What the hell...
ハラケン！
Haraken!
ハァ ハァ…
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway
通路が…
The passage...
これは…
This...
ハラケン？
Haraken!
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, ズレる:to slide/to slip off/to get dislocated
電脳の体がズレてる
Your cyberbody is...
shifting!
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
あのときと同じ
Just like back then!
（オバちゃん）待て
Wait!
電源を切る[でんげんをきる]:to turn off power
今は電源を切るな
Don't cut the power now.
新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from, 絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
（タケル）新しい空間に戻るまで
絶対にメガネを外さないこと
Until you come back,
never take the glasses off.
ポシェット:pochette/pouch (usu. hung from the shoulder by a long cord), メタタグ:META tag
ヤサコ…
ポシェットからメタタグを
Yasako...
Take the metatag out of my pocket...
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit
黒いやつ
The black one.
これ？
（ハラケン）うん
This?
戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
ズレが戻っていくわ
The shift is...
reversing.
なんともなかったか
So there wasn't any change.
場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 制御[せいぎょ]:control/governing/checking, ともかく:anyhow/anyway/somehow or other, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
場所の制御はともかく
通路は開いた
I couldn't control the location,
but at least the passage opened!
うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
うまくいってくれ
I hope everything goes well!
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, いったん:once|for a short time/briefly, いったん:one end/an end|part, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
（オバちゃん）
これだ　通路はいったん開いて…
This one.
The passage has opened once.
崩壊[ほうかい]:collapse/crumbling|decay
ハァ… 崩壊したか
It must've dissolved.
通行人[つうこうにん]:passerby/pedestrian/foot passenger, 事故[じこ, ことゆえ]:accident/incident|circumstances
（通行人１）
あれ？　なんだ また事故か？
Oh?
What's going on?
Another accident?
通行人[つうこうにん]:passerby/pedestrian/foot passenger, 信号機[しんごうき]:traffic light|signalling mechanism/semaphore (apparatus), 全く[まったく]:really|indeed|good grief (expression of exasperation), デタラメ:irresponsible utterance/nonsense/bullshit
（通行人２）
見ろ　信号機が全くデタラメだ
Look. The crossing light is totally messed up.
ともかく:anyhow/anyway/somehow or other, 行動[こうどう]:action/conduct/behaviour, 阻止[そし]:obstruction/check/hindrance
んん… ともかく
イサコの行動は阻止した
Anyway, I stopped Isako for now.
一時[ひととき, いっとき]:moment|former times|two-hour period, 一時[いちじ]:one o'clock|once|for a time|, 撤退[てったい]:evacuation/withdrawal/revocation
一時撤退だ
Retreat for now!
Yeah...
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, リンク:link/directory entry, 確立[かくりつ]:establishment/settlement|to establish
（猫目）ああ 通路は開いたのだが
リンクは確立しなかった
The passage did open,
but the link wasn't established.
引き続く[ひきつづく]:to continue (for a long time)/to occur in succession, モニター:(computer) monitor, 続ける[つづける]:to continue/to keep up/to keep on
引き続き モニターを続けてくれ
Continue to monitor the area.
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|, 厄介[やっかい]:trouble/burden|care, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
マズいな 厄介なことになった
Too bad.
This has become a big problem.
大丈夫？　ハラケン
Are you okay,
Haraken?
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
（ヤサコ）
ハラケン 体 どこか悪いの？
Haraken...
Do you have any physical symptoms?
なさる:to do
ご… ごめんなさい
言いたくないなら…
S-Sorry.
If you don't want to talk about it...
（ハラケン）
いいんだ　僕こそごめん
It's okay.
I'm sorry, too.
ぐらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, 心臓[しんぞう]:heart|guts|central part, 時々[ときどき]:sometimes/at times, 調子[ちょうし]:tune|vein|condition||, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
（ハラケン）１年前ぐらいから
心臓が 時々 調子悪いんだ
Since about a year ago,
sometimes my heart doesn't function properly.
例[れい]:custom|said|instance|, 例[ためし]:precedent/example, 立ちくらみ[たちくらみ]:dizziness (from standing up too fast)/orthostatic syncope/lightheadedness
（ヤサコ）例の立ちくらみって…
The famous...
dizziness?
心臓[しんぞう]:heart|guts|central part
（ハラケン）
うん 本当は心臓なんだ
Yeah.
In fact, it's my heart.
こないだ:the other day/lately/recently, 隣町[となりまち]:neighboring (adjacent) town/neighbouring town, 大学病院[だいがくびょういん]:university hospital/teaching hospital
でも こないだも
隣町の大学病院まで行って
But,
recently I had a complete examination at the university hospital.
精密検査[せいみつけんさ]:thorough checkup/complete examination/complete physical, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
精密検査してもらったけど
特に[とくに]:particularly/especially, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places, 見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
特に悪い所は
見つからなかったって
They didn't find any specific illness.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care, メガネ:spectacles/glasses
オバちゃんは すごく心配してさ
メガネのせいだって言ってる
My aunt is very worried.
She says it's all the fault of the glasses.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses
（ヤサコ）メガネの？
Of the glasses?
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 取り上げる[とりあげる]:to pick up|to adopt|to take away|
（ハラケン）
メガネ取り上げるとか言い出して
She says she wants to confiscate my glasses.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, ばっかり:only/merely|approximately, おかしい:funny/amusing|strange
自分こそメガネばっかりなのに
おかしいだろ？
Although she's got a one-track mind about glasses.
Strange, isn't it?
お兄さん[おにいさん]:older brother/elder brother|(vocative) young man, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
ねえ あのときの
天沢(あまさわ)さんのお兄さんの話
Say...
That story about Amasawa's older brother...
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
あっちに行ったまま
帰れなくなるって…
She says he ended up on "the other side" and can't come back anymore.
信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in
ハラケン 信じてるの？
Haraken, do you believe it?
都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
それって
都市伝説とか そういう…
Urban legends, and so on...
It's not something people usually believe in.
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, 信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in
普通 信じないよね こんなの…
Well, not exactly...
そんなことないけど
ハラケン
カンナちゃんに会いたいの？
Haraken,
do you want to meet Kanna?
かわいそう:poor/pitiable/pathetic
カンナちゃんは
かわいそうだと思う
I'm sorry for Kanna.
But you suffered for a whole year,
苦しむ[くるしむ]:to suffer/to groan/to be worried
でも ハラケンは
１年も苦しんだんだし もう…
so now...
ハラケン？
Haraken?
（ハラケン）ヤサコに
なんで そんなことが分かるの？
Yasako.
How come you know about this?
１年前にはいなかったのに
You weren't there a year ago.
場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 助け[たすけ]:assistance/help/aid, 求める[もとめる]:to want|to request|to seek|
カンナは
今もあの場所で助けを求めてる
Even now,
Kanna is still in that place,
asking for help.
埋め合わせる[うめあわせる]:to make amends/to compensate for/to make up for, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good
僕が埋め合わせなきゃ
いけないんだ
I have to work it out.
信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
信じてもらおうとは思ってない
I'm not saying
you should believe me.
（ヤサコ）ま… 待って！
そんなつもりで言ったんじゃないの
W-Wait!
I didn't mean it like that!
（オバちゃん）
んっ？　ケンちゃん？
Ken?
開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway
イサコが開いた通路に
どうしてケンちゃんが…
Why was Ken where Isako opened a passage?
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected
まさか…
It can't be true...
（ヤサコ）ハラケン
Haraken!
ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
何かできることがあったら
なんでも言って
If there's something I can do,
anything, please tell me!
We're friends after all.
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
友達なんだから
ハラケン 私…
Haraken,
I'm...
構う[かまう]:to mind|to care for|to prepare for||
もう構わないでほしいんだ
I just...
want you to leave me alone.
The independent research is all a lie.
自由[じゆう]:freedom/liberty/as it pleases you, 研究[けんきゅう]:study/research/investigation, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
自由研究なんて本当はウソなんだ
Haraken...
ハラケン
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
（ハラケン）ヤサコ ありがとう
Yasako, thank you.
You called me before, didn't you?
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
（ハラケン）
さっき呼んでくれただろ
助かる[たすかる]:to be saved|to escape harm|to be helped
あれで僕は
ちょっと助かったんだ
Somehow, that saved me.
Sorry.
ごめん
Entirely destroyed, three units.
全損[ぜんそん]:total loss, 基[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 基[き]:group|(free) radical|counter for installed or mounted objects (e.g. stone lanterns, gravestones, satellites)
（技師）全損３基 半損１基
Severely damaged, one unit.
始末書[しまつしょ]:written explanation or apology, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|
始末書じゃ済まんな
A damage report won't be enough for this.
Oh, hi.
顧問[こもん]:adviser/advisor/consultant
あっ 顧問
So the damage really was done from the inside.
やっぱり:too/also|still, 内部[ないぶ]:interior/inside/internal, 破壊[はかい]:destruction/disruption|(application) crash
やっぱり内部から破壊したんだ
From the inside?
内部[ないぶ]:interior/inside/internal
内部から？　でも それは…
But this-
...is impossible without the access code.
アクセス:access, コード:code
アクセスコードがないとできない
Ken...
ケンちゃん…
（フミエ）あっ ヤサコ
Yasako!
What've you been doing?
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
どうしたのよ？
電話 何度もかけたのよ
I called you so many times!
I couldn't even contact Haraken,
連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|, とれる:to come off/to be removed|(of pain, a fever, etc.) to disappear, とれる:to be photographed|to be able to photograph, 心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
ハラケンとも連絡とれないから
心配して…
and I was so worried!
Yasako?
ヤサコ？　なんかあったの？
Did something happen?
So, that one...
やっぱり:too/also|still
（ハラケン）
あれは やっぱりカンナだ
is really Kanna.
苦しい[くるしい]:painful|needy|forced (smile, joke)||, 助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|
（少女）苦しいの 助けて…
Save me...
You've been there all the time...
ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), あそこ:there (place physically distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|genitals, 苦しむ[くるしむ]:to suffer/to groan/to be worried
ずっと あそこにいたんだ
苦しんでる 今も
You're suffering.
Even now.
I'm the cause of your pain.
苦しめる[くるしめる]:to torment/to pain|to harass
僕が苦しめてる
I gotta go there again.
一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree
もう一度 行かなきゃ…
ハッ… オバちゃん
Aunty!
Why?
なぜ… なぜ こんなことをしたの？
Why did you do such a thing?
Ken, is it really so important to you?
大事[だいじ, おおごと]:important/valuable|safe (Tochigi dialect), なさる:to do
ケンちゃん 大事なことなの
本当のことを言いなさい
Tell me the truth.
I wanted to enter
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
古い空間に入りたかったんだ
the obsolete Space.
If I don't go...
僕が行かないと…
If I don't go, Kanna's suffering will never end!
苦しみ[くるしみ]:pain/anguish/distress, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
僕が行かないと
カンナの苦しみが終わらないんだ
Ken...
ケンちゃん カンナは死んだのよ
Kanna's dead.
The one who made her die...
カンナを死なせたのは 僕なんだ
is me.
Ken.
ケンちゃん
At the end, when we had a fight,
最後[さいご]:last|no sooner than|one's final moments, ケンカ:quarrel/brawl/fight
最後にケンカしたとき
僕 言ったんだ カンナに
I said
to Kanna,
"Don't always count on me."
頼る[たよる]:to rely on/to have recourse to/to depend on
“いつも僕に頼らずに―”
"Try to do things by yourself."
たまに:occasionally/once in a while, みせる:to show/to display
“たまには
１人で何かやってみせろ”って
And then...
行う[おこなう]:to perform/to do/to conduct oneself
それで…
それでカンナは１人で行ったんだ
Then Kanna went out alone and...
And despite this...
それなのに…
I promised Kanna's mother I'd find out the truth,
お母さん[おかあさん]:mother, 真相[しんそう]:truth/real situation, 突き止める[つきとめる]:to determine (esp. a culprit or underlying cause)/to pin down|to stab to death, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
カンナのお母さんに
“真相を突き止める”なんて
as if I was a good boy...
顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
いい顔したりして 僕は…
I'm...
ハッ… オバちゃん！
Auntie!
Give them back!
返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
返して 返して…
Give them back to me!
How could I possibly
死人[しにん, しびと]:corpse/dead person, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 渡す[わたす]:to ferry across (e.g. a river)|to lay across|to hand over
死人なんかに
あなたを渡してなるもんですか
give you to someone who's dead.
やはり:too/also|still, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
やはり通路を開いただけでは
ダメなのか
Indeed...
The passage opening isn't sufficient, huh...
暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, コントロール:control, 失う[うしなう]:to lose/to part with
暗号のコントロールを失ったわ
I lost control of the encode.
予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule, 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, 結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 間に合う[まにあう]:to be in time for|to serve (suit, meet) the purpose/to be good enough
予定と違う場所に開いて
結局 間に合わなかった
It opened in a different place than expected,
so I didn't get there in time.
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 局[きょく]:bureau|office (e.g. post, telephone)|affair|, 局[つぼね]:court lady|separate room in a palace (esp. for a lady) (Heian period)|room for a very low class prostitute|, 動き[うごき]:movement/move|trend, 封じる[ふうじる]:to seal (letter)|to prevent/to forbid, 封じる[ほうじる]:to enfeoff, 計画[けいかく]:plan/project/schedule
空間局の動きを
封じる計画だったんじゃないの？
In the plan, weren't you supposed to stop the Space Administration agents?
玉子[たまご]:eggs|hen egg|(an expert) in the making|, 作戦[さくせん]:tactics/strategy|military or naval operations, 無視[むし]:disregarding/ignoring
（猫目）すまない
玉子(たまこ)が作戦を無視したんだ
Sorry...
Tamako ignored the plan.
念[ねん]:sense|desire|attention, 少々[しょうしょう]:just a minute/small quantity, 細工[さいく]:work/craftsmanship/tactics
念のため サッチーには
少々 細工をしておいたんだが
Just to be sure, I placed some traps inside Satchii...
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
（イサコ）それでも通路は開いたわ
But the passage opened anyway.
リンク:link/directory entry, 再現[さいげん]:reappearance/reproduction/return
なぜリンクが再現しなかったの？
Why didn't the link appear?
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 全て[すべて]:everything/all|entirely
（猫目）通路のことは
僕らも全てを知らない
Even we don't know much about the passage.
基本的[きほんてき]:fundamental/standard/basic, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, やり方[やりかた]:manner of doing/way/method, 再現[さいげん]:reappearance/reproduction/return
基本的には先生のやり方を
再現してるだけなんだ
Basically, we're just recreating what the professor did.
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 間違う[まちがう]:to make a mistake/to be incorrect/to be mistaken
（イサコ）もしかして
暗号が間違ってるんじゃ…
Maybe
the encode is wrong?
以前[いぜん]:ago/since/before, 反応[はんのう, はんおう]:reaction/response, 方法[ほうほう]:method/process/manner, 間違い[まちがい]:mistake|accident|improper conduct (e.g. between man and woman)
（猫目）
以前も これで反応があったんだ
この方法で間違いはない
We already had a ping response from this in the past.
There's no doubt it's the right one.
残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left
キラバグは
あとどれだけ残っている？
How many kirabugs do you have left?
予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule, どおり:in accordance with/following|roughly, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 補強[ほきょう]:compensation/reinforcement
（イサコ）
予定どおり 通路を補強するために
As planned,
I only left one piece
残す[のこす]:to leave (behind, over)/to bequeath/to save
ひとカケラだけ残してあるわ
to reinforce the passage.
それを使えば…
If I use it...
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|
（猫目）いや 今はマズい
No, it's too dangerous right now.
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 不安定[ふあんてい]:instability/insecurity/crankiness, 予想外[よそうがい]:unexpected/unforeseen/strange, 事態[じたい]:situation/(present) state of affairs/circumstances, 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen, かねる:to be unable to/to find difficult (unpleasant, awkward, painful) to do|to serve two or more functions or roles simultaneously
まだ空間が不安定で
予想外の事態が起こりかねない
The Space is still unstable,
and the result may be unpredictable.
どういう:somehow/how/in what way, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
（イサコ）どういう意味？　猫目
What are you planning to do,
Nekome?
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 安定[あんてい]:stability/steadiness/equilibrium, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 恐らく[おそらく]:perhaps/likely/probably, 今夜[こんや]:this evening/tonight
（猫目）空間が安定するまでの間
恐らく今夜中に―
Until the Space returns to normal,
perhaps by tonight,
コントロール:control, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 再び[ふたたび]:again/once more/a second time, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, 危険性[きけんせい]:riskiness/danger
コントロールできない通路が
再び開く危険性がある
there's a danger that the passage will open once again.
（イサコ）なんだって？
What?
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, 送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||
ありがとう 送ってくれて
Thank you for taking me home.
今晩[こんばん]:tonight/this evening, 泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed
ヤサコ 今晩 泊まっていい？
（ヤサコ）えっ？
Yasako, can I sleep here tonight?
Oh?
今夜[こんや]:this evening/tonight
今夜は
京子(きょうこ)ちゃんしかいないんでしょ？
Tonight you're alone with Kyoko, right?
親戚[しんせき]:relative/relation/kin, 結婚式[けっこんしき]:marriage ceremony/wedding/nuptials
おじさんもおばさんも
親戚の結婚式で
Your parents are at a relative's marriage,
旅行[りょこう]:travel/trip
メガばあは旅行だって
言ってたじゃない
and Mega-baa is out traveling, right?
（ヤサコ）そうだけど でも…
Yes, but...
心配[しんぱい]:worry/concern|care
（フミエ）別に
あんたが心配だからじゃないわよ
It's not because I'm worried about you!
勝手[かって]:one's own convenience|surroundings|convenience||, 泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed
私が勝手に泊まりたいだけ
It's just that I want to sleep over.
フミエちゃん
Fumie...
ついで:next/secondly/subsequently, ついで:opportunity/occasion, たくさん:a lot/lots|enough, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
ついでに 今日は
たくさん話 聞いてあげるからさ
And you'll tell me a lot of things about today.
元気[げんき]:lively/full of spirit|healthy
ほら 元気 出せよ！
Come on, liven up!
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 反応[はんのう, はんおう]:reaction/response, 続く[つづく]:to continue|to continue (without a break)|to occur again and again||
（猫目）さっきの反応が
まだ続いているんだ
We are still receiving the ping response.
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, 特殊[とくしゅ]:special/particular/peculiar, リンク:link/directory entry, きっかけ:chance/start/cue
通路はキラバグの持つ
特殊なリンクがきっかけで―
Thanks to the special link the kirabug contains,
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 変質[へんしつ]:alteration (of character or essence)/change in quality/transformation, 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
古い空間に変質が起こって開く
the obsolete Space changes its form, and so the passage opens.
データ:data/datum, きっかけ:chance/start/cue
だが 今日のデータでは
きっかけはキラバグだけではない
But from the data collected today,
we learned that the trigger is not just the kirabug.
どういう:somehow/how/in what way, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
（イサコ）どういう意味？
What do you mean?
未知[みち]:not yet known/unknown/strange, 要因[よういん]:main cause/primary factor
（猫目）
何か もう１つの未知の要因
There is another unknown factor.
誘発[ゆうはつ]:cause/induce/lead up to, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
それに誘発されて通路は開くんだ
The passage opens because of that trigger.
制御[せいぎょ]:control/governing/checking, 暗号[あんごう]:code/password/cipher, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
制御暗号がない 今
どこに開くか分からない
Now that we don't have a control encode,
we don't know where will it open.
そんな…
That's absurd!
それじゃあ また
１年前のようなことに…
So it will happen like it did a year ago!
（猫目）そうはならない
Not really.
要因[よういん]:main cause/primary factor, 自体[じたい]:itself|one's own body|originally, めった:thoughtless/reckless|seldom (with neg. verb), 発生[はっせい]:outbreak|generation (e.g. of power or heat)|ontogeny
この要因自体
めったに発生しない
This trigger occurs rarely.
以前[いぜん]:ago/since/before, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 発生[はっせい]:outbreak|generation (e.g. of power or heat)|ontogeny, してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
でなければ
以前も もっと発生していたはずだ
Otherwise, it would have occurred more often in the past.
データ:data/datum, 蓄積[ちくせき]:accumulation/accumulate/store
ここは待つんだ
データの蓄積を待って…
We have to wait.
We've got to wait for the data-
（イサコ）ダメよ！
No way!
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen
もう 私のために
あんなことが起こるのはイヤ
Anyway,
I don't want to cause something like that...
用意[ようい]:preparation/arrangements/provision
だから あれだけ用意したのに…
That's why I collected so many...
気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
（猫目）待て どうする気だ？
Wait!
What do you want to...?
Cyber Urban Legends
らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
今日 うちの人が
誰もいないらしいから
Since her parents aren't home today,
泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
泊まってあげようと思って
I thought I'd better sleep at her place, for her sake.
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday
夏休みなんだし別にいいでしょ？
It's summer vacation, so there's no problem, right?
ああ… うん
いるのは京子ちゃんだけなのよ
Uh, yeah. There's only Kyoko.
うん 分かった
Okay.
声[こえ]:voice
声がしたよ
I heard a voice.
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, 苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of)
ううっ… やめてよ！
そういうの苦手なんだから
Stop it! I can't stand scary stuff!
おかしい:funny/amusing|strange, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 変質[へんしつ]:alteration (of character or essence)/change in quality/transformation
（イサコ）おかしい
どこにも空間の変質はない
It's strange.
There's no alteration in the Space at all.
場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
もし… もし また知らない場所に
開いたりしたら
Maybe...
if it opens in an unknown place,
しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
また あのときのようなことに
なってしまう
what happened the last time
could happen again.
手当[てあて]:salary|medical care|advance preparation, 次第[しだい]:depending on|as soon as|in accordance with||, 探す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
手当たり次第に探すしかない
I can't search everywhere randomly!
お前たち！
You!
（モジョたち）モジョ モジョ
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 見張る[みはる]:to stand watch/to stand guard|to open one's eyes wide, 異変[いへん]:unusual phenomenon/unusual event/abnormal event, 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen
（イサコ）古い空間を見張れ
異変が起こったら知らせるんだ
Patrol the obsolete Space!
Inform me at once if something happens!
行け！
Go!
（モジョたち）
モジョ モジョ モジョ…
おとなしい:obedient/docile/quiet, なさる:to do
（ヤサコ）ほら 京子
おとなしくしなさいって
Hey, Kyoko...
Be quiet already.
アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
アハハ～ ハハ～
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 髪の毛[かみのけ]:hair (head), 拭く[ふく]:to wipe/to dry
（フミエ）ダメよ！
ちゃんと髪の毛 拭かないと
No! If you don't dry your hair, you'll catch a cold!
風邪[かぜ, ふうじゃ]:common cold/cold/influenza, 引く[ひく]:to pull|to draw (attention, etc.)|to draw back||
風邪 引くわよ
なさる:to do
（フミエ）こら 来なさい！
（京子）うわっ…
Come on, come!
寝る[ねる]:to lie down|to go to bed|to sleep (lying down)||, 潰す[つぶす]:to smash|to shut down|to thwart||
（ヤサコ）
デンスケがそばで寝てるからね
潰しちゃダメよ
Densuke is sleeping by your side,
so don't crush him.
やっぱり:too/also|still
（フミエ）やっぱり出ない？
（ヤサコ）うん
He's not answering...
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 自由[じゆう]:freedom/liberty/as it pleases you, 研究[けんきゅう]:study/research/investigation, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
あいつ ホントに言ったのね？
“自由研究なんてウソだ”って
Did he really say so?
That the independent research is a lie?
どういう:somehow/how/in what way
どういうつもりよ
What's on his mind?
かげん:(moon's) last quarter, かげん:lower limit|infimum
いいかげんなヤツだとは
思ってたけど
I thought he was a good boy, but now...
そんなんじゃないの
（フミエ）えっ？
He is.
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, ズレる:to slide/to slip off/to get dislocated, 都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
体がズレる都市伝説 知ってる？
Do you know the urban legend about a body shifting?
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
あっちに行っちゃうって話？
The story about ending up to "the other side"?
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, ズレる:to slide/to slip off/to get dislocated
（ヤサコ）
今日 ハラケンの体がズレてたの
Today,
Haraken's body shifted.
Eh?
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 現実[げんじつ]:reality/actuality/hard fact
電脳の体と現実の…
His cyberbody and his real one.
脅かす[おどかす]:to threaten/to menace|to startle, 脅かす[おびやかす]:to intimidate/to scare|to jeopardize, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of, 苦手[にがて]:poor (at)/weak (in)|dislike (of)
ヤダ… 脅かす気？
私 そういうの苦手なんだから
Crap, are you trying to scare me?
I really hate that stuff.
そういうわけじゃないんだけど
I didn't mean to do that.
交差点[こうさてん]:crossing/intersection
（フミエ）
ヤサコ 交差点で何があったの？
Yasako,
what happened at the crossing?
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 鍵穴[かぎあな, カギあな]:keyhole, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
見たの 黒い鍵穴みたいなものを
I saw it.
I saw a thing like a black keyhole.
それって…
Maybe...
Exactly like those kids' drawings?
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 子供[こども]:child/children, 絵[え]:picture/drawing/painting, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
まさか あの子供の絵と同じ？
映像[えいぞう]:reflection|video|image in one's mind
（ヤサコ）分からない
でも ただの映像じゃない
I don't know...
But it's not a simple image.
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
この黒い穴は
ただ電脳空間にあるものじゃないわ
That black keyhole doesn't just belong to cyberspace.
映像[えいぞう]:reflection|video|image in one's mind, 一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
（フミエ）ただの映像でなきゃ
一体なんなのよ？
If it's not just an image, then what on earth is it?
意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 影響[えいきょう]:influence/effect|to influence, 与える[あたえる]:to give (esp. to someone of lower status)|to provide|to assign||
（ヤサコ）
意識に影響を与えるんだわ
It has an impact on our consciousness.
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
や… やめてよ
Cut it out...
病気になる[びょうきになる]:to fall ill/to be taken ill, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
（ヤサコ）
ハラケンは病気になりかけてる
The illness Haraken is experiencing
病気[びょうき]:illness/disease/sickness
それも ただの病気じゃない
is not a normal illness.
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|
あの黒い穴から…
From that black hole,
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
黒い穴の中から
何かがハラケンを呼んでるんだわ
from the middle of that hole,
something is calling Haraken!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
（フミエ）
ヤ… ヤサコ やめてってば！
Yasako, I told you to stop it already!
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, つながる:to be tied together/to be connected to|to lead to
（ヤサコ）あの黒い穴の中は
きっと違う世界につながっている
The inside of that black hole
is certainly linked to another world.
子供たち[こどもたち]:children, 絵[え]:picture/drawing/painting, ホント:truth/reality/actuality
あの子供たちの絵が
もしホントに見たものなら
If those kids' drawings are really what they saw...
きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.)
きっと あの先には
死んだ人がいて…
On the other side there are dead people.
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
や… やめて！
St-Stop it!
How could that possibly be?
そんなことあるわけないじゃない
Yasako, you're strange!
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
ヤサコ 変よ
フミエちゃん
Fumie...
まるで:quite/entirely|as if, 都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
そんなの まるで都市伝説よ
That stuff is nothing more than an urban legend!
思い出す[おもいだす]:to recall/to remember/to recollect, 最近[さいきん]:most recent/these days/right now
私 思い出したの 最近…
I
remembered.
Lately...
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
（ヤサコ）私 この黒い穴
初めてじゃないの
This is not
the first time
I saw that black hole.
ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
見たことがあるの
I saw it before.
When I was little,
小さい[ちいさい]:small/little/tiny, 頃[ころ, ごろ]:(approximate) time|suitable time (or condition)|time of year, 頃[けい]:qing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu), メガネをかける:to wear glasses/to put on glasses, 捜す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
小さい頃 メガネをかけて
デンスケを捜しに行って
I was wearing glasses, and I went looking for Densuke...
I thought it was a dream.
夢[ゆめ]:dream
夢だと思ってた　だけど…
But...
I'm certain that something is there!
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness
絶対 何かある
There's a secret hidden in that black hole!
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, 秘密[ひみつ]:secret|secret|esoteric teachings
あの黒い穴には何か秘密が…
A-A blackout?
停電[ていでん]:power outage/electricity outage/blackout
て… 停電？
The glasses are working...
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
メガネは生きてる
霧[きり]:fog/mist|spray, 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places
んっ？　なんで霧がこんな所に…
Why is there fog here?!
Densuke!
デンスケ！
Evening glow?
夕焼け[ゆうやけ]:evening glow/red sunset/afterglow (of sunset)
（フミエ）夕焼け？
Kyoko?!
京子… ハッ！
What is...
（フミエ）何… これ？
this?
Kyoko!
京子…
Preview
Next time
on Dennou Coil:
The black visitors.
The Black Visitors
See you next time!
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, コイル:coil
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 訪問者[ほうもんしゃ]:visitor
〝黒い訪問者 〞
楽しみ[たのしみ]:enjoyment/pleasure|anticipation
お楽しみに